<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<toolset id="user_apps_toolset" template="false">
   <tool app_file_path="gui/combustion_toolbox_app.mlapp" handler_class="com.mathworks.deployment.desktop.toolstrip.ToolboxToolSetExtensionHandler" id="1cf6bd40-0896-49b0-957b-4fe2f3ead1fe:gui/combustion_toolbox_app.mlapp" label="Combustion Toolbox" quick_access_eligible="false" toolset_id="user_apps_toolset">
      <callback>combustion_toolbox_app</callback>
      <summary>Combustion Toolbox: an open source thermochemical code for solving gaseous combustion problems</summary>
      <description>Combustion Toolbox (CT) is a new thermochemical code that can be used to solve gaseous combustion and related problems involving chemical equilibrium of gas- and condensed-phase species. The kernel of the code is based in NASA's computer program CEA (Chemical Equilibrium with Applications). The thermochemical properties are computed within the ideal gas approximation using an up-to-date version of NASA’s 9-coefficient polynomial fits. These fits use the Third millenium database, which include the available values from Active Thermochemical Tables. Combustion Toolbox is written in MATLAB with a modular architecture composed of three main modules: CT-EQUIL, CT-SD, CT-ROCKET. The core module, CT-EQUIL, minimizes the Gibbs/Helmholtz free energy of the system using Lagrange multipliers combined with a multidimensional Newton-Raphson method, upon the condition that the mixture properties are defined by two functions of state (e.g., enthalpy and pressure). CT-SD solves processes that involve strong changes in dynamic pressure, such as steady state shock and detonation waves in either normal or oblique stream configurations within the limits of regular shock reflections. Finally, CT-ROCKET estimates rocket propellant performance under ideal conditions. The tool has been equipped with a versatile Graphical User Interface and has been successfully used for both teaching and research activities during the last three years. Results are in excellent agreement with the CEA code, CANTERA within Caltech's Shock and Detonation Toolbox (SD-Toolbox), and the recent Thermochemical Equilibrium Abundances (TEA) code. CT is available under an open-source GPLv3 license via Github https://github.com/AlbertoCuadra/combustion_toolbox and its documentation can be found in https://combustion-toolbox-website.readthedocs.io.</description>
      <icon filename="matlab_app_generic_icon_24"/>
      <icon filename="matlab_app_generic_icon_16"/>
      <parent_tool id="my_apps" toolset_id="apps_toolset"/>
   </tool>
</toolset>